# THEODORE JOHNSON

SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER



#### **SUMMARY**

A senior software engineer with 7 years of professional experience, specializing in full-stack development, **React**, **Angular**, **Node** and **Python**. A proven track record of managing large-scale software engineering projects to support cloud deployments and integrations.



## **SKILLS**

- React / Next / Angular / Vue
- Node / Express / Nest
- PHP / Laravel

- Python / Django / Fast API
- WordPress / KeystoneJS
- AWS / Lambda / SNS / SQS



## **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Full Stack Engineer | Topflight

SEP 2020 - PRESENT

- Collaborated with a cross-functional team to design and develop the Geocoding Service for a GPS tracking system, utilizing **React**, and **AWS**.
- Implemented a robust CI/CD pipeline using **Jenkins**, **Docker**, and **Kubernetes**, enabling automated builds, testing, and deployment of applications.
- Boosted platform performance with AWS Elastic Load Balancer, Redis caching, and CDN (content delivery network) resulting in a 70% improvement in speed and responsiveness.
- Utilized **KeystoneJS** and **Next** to develop a customized CMS for an insurance company, streamlining their business processes.
- Minimized round trips by leveraging GraphQL and utilizing declarative data fetching
  queries to efficiently retrieve relevant data, enabling seamless integration with multiple
  third-party services.
- Developed a scheduling system for travel agencies using AWS Lambda, Step Functions, and SQS, enabling efficient management of bookings, itineraries, and availability.
- Conducted unit testing, integration testing, and end-to-end (E2E) testing using industrystandard libraries and frameworks such as **Jest**, **Pytest**, and **Cypress**.
- Worked in a cross-functional team of a tech startup, collaborated efficiently, resulting in a 25% team productivity increase and a 30% saving of meeting time
- Mentored junior team members through code reviews, pair coding, and one-on-one conversations, resulting in improved work quality, optimized pull-requests, and consistently high standards.

## Full Stack Engineer | Geniusee

JAN 2018 – SEP 2020

- Worked with product managers to re-architect a multi-page web-app into a single page utilizing **Laravel** and **Vue**, boosting yearly revenue by \$1.4M
- Worked on the payments team to save time and improve cash flow for over 50,000 through the development of modern, responsive customer experiences
- integrated existing software, built with **Django** and **Angular**, into 13 upgraded and modified systems to improve their performance.

## Frontend Engineer | Kinship

JUN 2016 – JAN 2018

- Contributed to the in-house **React** UI library to create reusable components that saved 125+ hours of development per month
- Created a web app MVP for a store delivery management platform with 200+ business customers to create, manage, and monitor deliveries using **React** and **Redux**
- Improved customer conversion rate by 17% through A/B testing of different components, representing \$500,000+ in incremental annual revenue



# **EDUCATION**

Stockholm University 2016
BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE